SAM KAUFFMAN

hello@samvk.com http://samvk.com 860-878-8669 West Hartford, CT 06107

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic coder who enjoys problem solving and bringing others' designs to life. Sam has experience building for the web using the basic front-end technologies HTML(5), CSS(3), and JavaScript(ES6)—amped up with the help of Sass(SCSS) and jQuery. He's in the process of learning PHP & MySQL to become a better front-end coder and possible full-stack developer.

Feel free to check me out on GitHub at http://github.com/samvk or take a look at my portfolio at http://samvk.com.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Front-End Web Developer

Greater Hartford, CT

2015 – Present

- Performing front-end maintenance and upgrades for existing websites
- Developing mobile-friendly responsive websites
- Basic back-end management
- **Technical Skills:** HTML(5), CSS(3), Sass(SCSS), & JavaScript(ES6) + jQuery

Technology Specialist

March 2016 - Present

CREC Data Center, Hartford, CT

- Troubleshooting and resolving issues related to computer software and hardware
- Performing desktop and laptop re-imaging tasks
- Installing software updates and hardware upgrades on end user machines
- Utilizing software such as Remote Desktop Connection to resolve issues remotely

Mathematics Associate Instructor

2015 - Present

CREC Metropolitan Learning Center, Bloomfield, CT

- Supporting high school students in the strengthening of math skills and conceptual understandings through differentiated learning
- Integrating technology into the classroom to help visualize, analyze, and interpret data and become data literate
- Gathering and entering school data to track long-term student growth

Easy Tech and Sales Associate

February – September 2014

Staples Inc, Lancaster, PA

- Staying current on new technologies
- Resolving computer hardware, software, and operating system issues
- Determining and fulfilling client needs
- Friendly customer service

Technical Assistant 2011 – 2015

F&M Schnader Theatre, Lancaster, PA

- Operating sound board and A/V equipment
- Rigging audio systems and management of wireless microphone frequencies
- Optimizing and troubleshooting lighting and rendering problems
- Running of cables and house & backline management

EDUCATION

Franklin and Marshall College

- B.A. in Technical Theatre and Design
- Graduated cum laude